So we completed a differentization and discovery tactics and we now moving on to impact
that library section sorry the lateral moment session so most of the lateral moment will
be happening through impact at library but this library needs some information like the
user name domain name and passwords anyway we got the information from the
credential access section you will be seeing we used pipecats and few other
credential access methods to gather the username and passwords from the local
machine so in this section we are going to use these credentials to move
laterally from one machine to another machine so think of it you have a domain
administrator credentials and you need to move to the machine inside an
organization so you need some kind of protocol some kind of application or
some kind of network port or to move from this machine to another machine okay so
impact will give you give you a easy easy methods to move from one machine to
another because it will it's a collection of network protocols and the
impact at libraries designed with Python classes and it will very well work
with the network protocols and it's one of a powerful very very powerful toolkit
and a library that will remotely execute a command from one machine to another
machine so let's think of it you are using a Kali Linux machine and your
target was a Windows machine but impact library will be supporting the
native language what windows were supporting example and SMB so in Kali Linux
our Linux based operating system we have an SMB as well as the windows operating
machines will be also supporting the SMB protocols right so we can interact
with the with the machine through the native windows services like SMB or
WHIC or anything okay so you don't need to install any kind of third-party
applications to get access get moved laterally from this machine to another
machine impact libraries enough to move and go ahead okay so this comes with
our Kali Linux defaultly but some of the Kali Linux still we need an
we need an installation so installation of pretty simple units to install the
pseudo APT install Python 3 impact it so it's it's it's a quite simple okay so
once you install the impact at library so you can you can see how much how much
thing it was supporting AT-exect DCOM-exect DPA-PA here you can find
MimiCads NetView PS-exect so the next in this section we are going to use few
of the impact at libraries to move laterally from this machine to another
machine okay so PS-exect and SMB-exect and SMB-clined RDP check is SAM or the SAM
dump secret of many many options or they are to support to move to help us to move
from one machine to another okay so let's use a credential access tactics we
already gathered the domain name as well as the username and password from the
machine in the similar way once you got domain administrator
pencils your target will be moving to an admission to another machine let me
show you some other things why we what are the libraries what's supporting the
impact okay so let's think about the PS-exect we are going to use PS-exect in
the in this session so PS-exect is also enough really really very really famous
tool it directly interact with the command shell CMD.exe or PowerShell.exe on
remote machine okay so basically it will install a small service inside the
machine and we'll get a reverse connection so let's go to another another one SMB
Exect it will be similar to a PS-exect and it will be using the SMB-exect
protocol let I will attach this hacker recipient article so this is one of
good article which you can read why what about the impact libraries and
why and which situations he needs to use this okay so if any of some faced
interview questions what is an impact that you can directly say it's a
collection of Python libraries supporting major network protocols to move
laterally from one machine to another it's enough to move laterally from one
machine to another also we can steal credentials we can we can do some
some things like lateral movement okay so this could be a best explanation so
you can say PS-exect SMB-exect a few of the next sample that will be supporting
impact library so let's go from here we'll jump on to another next video to see
how the impact it will be okay so thanks for watching we'll connect you guys in
the next video bye